KUZURYU HIGH SCHOOL
Chemistry Club
Sweet
Tea
Hm? From the gym?
This early in the morning?
Oh crap! Mokichi!
Back to the mirror, my dream getting
farther with every step I take
I want to come face-to-face with you
Saying to the incapable version
of myself, "never mind"
Ahiru no Sora
A dream slowly dismantled
on the assembly line
(Suitable? Unsuitable?
Pretty much impossible?)
True feelings gone missing without a whisper
(Not even capable of a sigh)
None of it will end by
placing the blame on others
Right now, in the face of a steep slope
My heart cries out for me to "overcome it"
Finding excuses not to try is
something that anybody can do
Pushing myself to run beyond, I
went to meet a me I've never known
There's graffiti etched on the
wall that says "never mind"
Now, I bounce into tomorrow
A-a-are you okay?!
Morning practice?
The Moon and the Hoop
Yeah, since the prelims are coming up fast.
Did you get hurt at all, dude?
Oh, let me introduce you.
This is Momoharu, our team captain.
Oh... um...
He said "Good morning, sir."
Uh, yeah, same to you.
So, I hear you used to shoot hoops?
Well, feel free to join us.
No... I didn't come here
to play with you guys or anything.
Huh?
I just always come to school
around this time in the morning.
What? Every day?
Yeah.
Let him do what he wants.
Two of our usual clowns are sleeping in,
so we're down players anyway.
We can play 3-on-3 if he's in.
Let's play together, Mokichi!
Since it's so early in the morning,
we can use the whole court to our heart's content!
I've already quit... playing basketball.
Huh? But why?
You're really good at it!
No doubt about that.
The fact he can get the ball in the basket
already makes him better than Momoharu.
Totally.
Asswipes...
My doctor told me... that I shouldn't play.
Kuzuryu High School Boys' Basketball Team
I've always had a frail constitution
and I don't handle physical exercise very well.
So that's why...
Huh? But wait, didn't you tell me
that you've played basketball since grade school?
I did, to try and help me build some stamina.
I'm guessing that didn't work.
Not even in the slightest...
I can't live up to your
expectations. I'm sorry.
Playing high school basketball...
isn't a possibility for me.
Man, what a bummer...
I was really looking forward
to shooting hoops with Mokichi.
Not everybody's fit for the court.
Actually, when we met in the gym yesterday,
Mokichi said that he was jealous of me.
Just imagine all the practice he went through
to get good at hook shots.
I have no doubt... he must love basketball.
Seriously?! They're mine?!
Awesome!
That's okay. Because I...
...don't need to wear them anymore.
Loving a sport but being unable to play it...
...I know how he feels.
How's that? Somebody you know
have a similar problem?
Huh? Uh, not at all!
I was just imagining what it must be like.
Happens all the time.
Lots of players have to retire due to illness
or back and knee injuries.
Loving a sport ain't
enough to keep you in it.
Now that I think about it,
mom hasn't been sending me many replies lately.
Does that mean she hasn't been feeling well?
Wow. This is a surprise.
What inspired you two to start playing shogi?
We're betting our lunch on it.
I already won, though.
What the-?!
Sorry, I didn't mean to just
steal your seat, Nanao.
Oh, don't worry about it. Anyways...
I just picked this up from Mr.
Satsuki a few minutes ago.
The tournament bracket is out!
Prelims! Prelims! Prelims!
Shut up!
Our first opponent will be...
Shinmaruko
Shinjotowa
Kuzuryu
Shinmaruko
Shinjotowa
Kuzuryu
Maru High is in the same block that we are...
Wh-wh-what about Kitasumi?!
Yes! They're in another block!
We're safe from dealing with
any of them for a while then!
You can't avoid the inevitable, guys.
What kind of team are we
facing in the first round?
Don't you have data on them or something?
Uh, well, Shinjotowa is a team that...
has 3 players in the 190 cm range.
I know that one of them is 196 cm tall.
The average height of
their sophomore players is 184 cm.
So, we're dealing with a team of giants.
Too many kids going through
ridiculous growth spurts these days.
You're one to talk.
All right. Let's get to practicing!
Hold up. I don't see Kite anywhere.
Kite's busy right now.
He got stuck with extra lessons today.
Hah! Guess he's an idiot
outside of basketball.
You guys should consider following his example.
Mid-terms are next week, you know?
Are you serious?!
Hey, Chucky! You're defending too high!
Pay more attention to the
distance you're leaving!
Hiyah!
Yasuhara, that's your 7th foul today!
Drop and give me 20 more push-ups right now!
Next! 2-on-2!
Rotate positions!
There's pretty much no time
left before the prelims.
What do you think, do we stand a shot?
To be perfectly frank, it
will be an uphill battle.
Right... you really cut to the point.
I think the biggest obstacle at this point
is our lack of height.
We only have 3 players on the team
who come in at over 180 centimeters.
We were able to go up against Kitasumi
on pretty even terms in that regard,
but the only reason that worked out
is because Kitasumi is on the short side overall.
Our first match in the prelims
is going to be completely different.
Especially under the basket.
If that's the case, then we really need somebody with height,
even if it's not that Mokichi guy.
You're right.
Well, we shouldn't waste time
worrying about what we don't have.
So let's work hard to overcome
any challenges on our own.
Considering how high you can jump, it's pretty much
like having two players for the price of one.
Trust me.
Oh-ho?
That's some high praise coming from you.
But your lack of scoring ability practically
puts us down a player,
so we come out even in the end.
Ouch...
Extra Lessons
You have a good head on your shoulders.
'Course, I do.
Listen up.
You were suspended for two weeks
immediately after school started.
If you don't put some effort into studying,
you'll get left behind quickly.
And don't forget... I'm holding you
to your promise of not getting into any fights.
I haven't forgotten.
The prelims are about to start,
I'm not gonna throw it all away for a fight.
A'ight, time to head for the gy-
Wow!
I didn't know that!
Take this and then put it over
in this one, and it's done.
It's the beanstalk...
Incredible! You really did it!
You've got a real knack for this, Mokichi!
Most definitely, everybody around here
considers you the ace of the chem club!
"Ace"?
Can a chemistry club even have an "ace"...?
This reminds me, Mokichi.
I hear that you turned down
the basketball team on their offer yesterday.
I was really surprised.
I had no idea that your physical condition
was bad enough
that the doctor made you stop playing...
Oh, but hey, you're safe with us!
We'll never make you do anything
too strenuous around here, Mokichi.
That was a lie.
Huh?
I lied. About the doctor.
You lied? But why would you do that?
Because teams always quit trying to recruit me
after I tell them that.
Quit trying?
Well isn't that an interesting story?
Start 'splaining it to me.
Wh-who are you and why are you here?
I'm just here to chat with the beanstalk.
Why the hell would you lie to us?
If you didn't want to play,
then you could've just told us that straight up.
It's really... none of your business.
You're right about that.
I don't give a single shit
about you or your problems.
But some of us believed in you
and really took that lie to heart, jackass!
What's going on?! What was that noise?!
S-Sir! Please do something about him!
Oh shit, this is bad...
Ugh! What is that smell?!
I'm very sorry.
I was clumsy and accidentally
spilt ammonia solution on him.
Please forgive me.
Forget it. No big deal.
Dammit.
Why the hell am I getting all bent out of shape
on behalf of the shrimp?
Sorry to bother you, Nanao.
Can you pass them to me from further away?
Sure. I can do that.
Kurumatani is different today.
He's incredibly focused...
...don't need to wear them anymore.
My doctor told me... that I shouldn't play.
Hard to believe he can sink
threes like that at his height.
His skills are really... impressive.
Whoa, check him out.
He's gotta be at least 2 meters tall, yeah?
Wish we had somebody like him
on our school's volleyball team.
What am I, chopped liver?
Must be nice to reap all
the benefits of being tall.
So annoying...
Huh? Hey, asshole! What did you just say?!
He's, like, kind of creepy.
You want me to kick your
ass to the curb, punk?
Uh, no, I...
Not again...!
C'mon, shithead. Answer my damn question.
Ew, gross. What's his problem?
Enough bullshit, hurry up and say something!
Ugh, just forget this loser
and let's get out of here.
Freaks like this make me wanna puke.
Could say the same about you.
Total barf bags!
Huh...?
Sweet, that was worth the trip.
I thought for sure her
panties would be black.
Yo! What the hell are you doing to my woman?!
Who the hell decided that she was YOUR woman?
Wh-who do you think...?
See? I told you we shouldn't bother.
Guys like us just aren't cut
out for this hero stuff.
We got a peek at some panties,
so I consider it a win.
Man, I missed tonight's
"Kumagoro Animal Nation"...
Please turn... right...
Dude, you better not just
be faking it. I'll drop you!
This is my house...
Hot damn, are you one of those
super rich kids or what?
I could smell piles of cash
coming from this guy a mile away.
Good evening.
For real?!
Let's claim a little
reward. For our good deed.
Holy shit! A private court?!
We're still in Japan, right?
Dudes, let's try out our
footwork on this thing!
We just finished doing all that at practice!
No way, this can't be real.
Just how much money does his family have?!
Who's there?!
Oh my, are all you boys from Kaname's school?
Yes, ma'am! We're his good friends!
Oh no! He collapsed at school again?!
Yes. And we're the ones
who made sure he got home safely!
Dear madam, allow me to offer my assistance.
You cheat! I'm the one who carried him all t-
No, it was me who did!
Quit lying!
You're the liar!
Th-thank you, boys...
You!
Excuse my bluntness, but
may I have your name?
I'm Kaname's older sister, my name is Sayuri.
A beautiful name.
Um, so is this court like...
part of your house?
That's right.
Kaname was still just an elementary student.
It was an outrageous request, but our father did it for him.
How is a private basketball court "outrageous"
instead of just plain "impossible"...?
After that, he would play around out there every day,
from morning until night.
Wow.
And in middle school,
he went to this place
called Saijo known for their tough basketball team.
Seriously?! This guy went to Saijo?!
Even in 6th grade, he was already
upwards of 180 centimeters tall.
So delicious! Delectable!
So in middle school, he was
made a starter right away.
He was a shining star, with the hopes
of the team and school riding on him.
I also thought...
Stop it!
Kaname!
Hearing that stuff... really aggravates me.
Nobody gave any thought to how I felt,
nor how hard it was to deal with everyone's expectations.
All I ever wanted to do... was
just play some basketball.
Seijo
Miyasakae
And yet...!
He can't run worth a shit.
All he's got is height.
People kept expecting so much of me
and then were disappointed all on their own!
Kaname...
That sounds pretty nice, man.
Nobody even bothers...
to expect anything from guys like us.
That's for damn sure.
We're basically just a
pimple on society's ass.
But that doesn't stop us from
trying to win the inter-high.
It's almost funny, eh?
The inter-high...
Yo, let us get in on some of the fun.
What do they mean by that?
Sure.
You wanna put 5,000 funbucks down on this?
I thought that Kuzu High
didn't have a boys' basketball team.
Bring it. I'll bet all the funbucks you want.
I thought that's why you applied there.
Don't underestimate the
power of funbucks, Momoharu.
To give up on ever playing basketball again.
Yeah, but...
...it turns out there
is... a basketball team.
BOYS'
BASKETBALL
TEAM
He lied?
All that stuff about the doctor was BS.
That stupid beanstalk really pisses me off.
Why would he even bother
to lie to us like that?
Cuz he's a 2-meter-tall freshman.
Any high school would kill to have him.
Just putting him on a team
would help motivate the other members.
With a ton of expectations piled up like that,
anybody would snap from the pressure.
Just like that.
It doesn't matter whether he's sick or not.
If he's not interested in joining,
then there's nothing we can do.
Hey, Kite.
Did Mokichi really say all that stuff?
Why the hell would I lie
to you about what he said?
C'mon dude, just forget that beanstalk.
Only 4 seconds left... only
one chance left to score!
I gotta block!
Yeah!
We did it!
Just a dream...?
Oh yeah... I took the day
off from school today...
Nobody even bothers...
to expect anything from guys like us.
But that doesn't stop us from
trying to win the inter-high.
It's almost funny, eh?
I wonder... are they serious...?
Welcome.
Basketball shoes these days...
seem kind of futuristic.
I can get your size, if
you'd like to try them on.
I bet you must be about a 30?
Uh, no thanks.
I'm just looking.
I don't play basketball anymore.
Oh, is that so? That's a
shame, since you're so tall.
Sorry to bother you.
Ah! These ones! These are
the shoes our Senpai has!
Is that you, Shigeyoshi?
Tsu-Tsukishima?!
Wow! It's been, like, forever!
I'm so surprised to see you!
What are you doing out here?
Who's this? An old classmate of yours, Kyoko?
That's right! From back in middle school!
C'mon, say hello!
Uh, my name is Kanam-
Speak up!
You haven't changed. Your eyebrows
are as thick as ever, Senpai.
Shut it!
Are you sure, about leaving
your friend behind?
Oh, she's fine, don't worry.
I've got other plans today, anyways.
But hey, I wanna know!
You were looking at basketball shoes earlier, right?
Does this mean that you
started playing again?!
No, uh, it's just a habit that I've had
ever since I was young...
...hanging out in shoe stores like that
helps calm me down.
Boo!
Don't get my hopes up like that!
I had such big expectations for you.
Now I'm just super disappointed.
So I'm curious, do you remember?
Our summer vacation in 2nd year?
There was this big rumor that spread through the whole
girls' team about how you had a huge crush on me.
Th-th-th-th-th-that was just gossip, I swear.
Huh? So you didn't?!
Th... That's right...
Darn, that's too bad.
Then... how about right now?
Huh?
Uh, no, actually, well... honestly,
I don't feel any different about you now as I did back then.
That's totally not what
I was asking you about!
I meant sports!
Are you playing on any other teams right now?
Uhhh... well... the chemistry club.
Is that fun for you?
Yes. It's something... I enjoy.
Oh?
More than basketball?
It's fun... even more than basketball.
I see.
Then I'm happy for you!
No... actually...!
Kyoko!
What're you doing? The library's gonna close.
Oh shoot! I totally spaced!
Gotta study for the test!
Give me a break already, jeez.
You're the one who asked
me to help you study.
You remember him, right, Shigeyoshi?
This is Fujita, another
senior from middle school.
Uh, nice to see you.
Actually, we've been dating
each other recently.
See you later, Shigeyoshi!
Uh, sure.
Who was that?
He was a freshman
at our school, remember? Shigeyoshi!
Oh, right. You mean Mokichi, the one who...
That's not his name!
Kaname?
He's 180 cm tall, dude!
That's nuts!
The size of the court and length of games
is a step up from junior basketball.
You'll get used to it.
Just work on building up your stamina, man.
Dammit, right when we needed him!
Don't be like that.
It's what we get for relying on a freshman.
Again, really?
It's fine. Just go home today.
He hasn't improved at all this year, I swear.
Doesn't he understand that he's
on the verge of being left behind?
I am... such an idiot.
The one person who I disappointed
the most... was myself.
I've gotta get back there... one more time.
No matter what!
Even if things aren't going well on my own
There's a simple way to turn it all around
A light falls down on an
exit previously unseen
That's where the path to tomorrow lies
I was never really alone to begin with
You were in the scenery reflected in my eyes
I can go anywhere so long as you stay there
There are no such things as limits
Just having you by my side makes me stronger
We'll pick ourselves up as
often as needed and keep moving
Oh oh oh, oh oh oh, oh oh oh,
Until the very last second
Don't give up and keep fighting
A shining light is undoubtedly
waiting for us down this path
Ahiru no Sora
Next Time: Light
Next time: "Light."